artsonia.com 2017-04-07

# Artsonia - Privacy Policy

#### Privacy Policy

At Artsonia, we are committed to protecting every User's privacy. We use the information we collect to process orders and to provide a more personalized service. Artsonia's Privacy Policy, set forth below, is designed to use the information we collect about visitors with the utmost care and responsibility. All capitalized terms that are not defined in the Privacy Policy below shall have the meanings given in the Terms and Conditions of Use. 

**1\. Information Provided By All Users of the Website**

The information Users provide to Artsonia through Artsonia.com or through certain mobile applications created by Artsonia (collectively referred to as the "Website") is used to process orders, to provide enhanced and more personalized service, and to properly index and display artwork, lesson plans, and other materials. 

The information Users provide to Artsonia is solely for Artsonia's internal business use. We do not sell this information to anyone. 

Fan Club Membership: When visiting the Website, Users may join an Artist's Fan Club. Fan Club members receive email alerts when an Artist publishes new artwork, adds or updates an Artist statement or receives a Comment. In addition, the first name (that is, whatever name a member types into the "first name" field in the fan club enrollment) of the Fan Club member is publicly listed in the Artist's gallery. In addition, the full name and email of the Fan Club Member may be revealed to the Artist's Parent. In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), children under 13 are not allowed to join a Fan Club on the Website. 

Artsonia may disclose personal information if we believe, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to enforce or apply the terms of Artsonia's user agreements (including without limitation the Terms and Conditions of Use) or to protect the property, rights or safety of Artsonia, its Users or others. 

**2\. Information Provided By Teachers**

Any Teacher (as defined in the Terms and Conditions of Use) who wishes to display their students' artwork, lesson plans or other educational material s on Artsonia is required to register as a member. The information provided during the registration process is used to communicate with the Teacher as well as to create a school gallery on Artsonia, which will list the Teacher's name and the name of the school. Teachers should be aware that, because personal information about themselves (i.e., their name and school) is posted on the Website and is publicly accessible to all users of the Website, that information could be collected, used, and disclosed by others. Artsonia is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of such information. Artsonia does not publicly post Teachers' email addresses on the Website, and does not sell or share that list with third parties except where Teachers have explicitly authorized Artsonia to share their email addresses with our marketing partners. 

The following conditions also apply to Teachers that choose to upload class artwork: 

  * To organize artwork, Teachers input first and (optionally) last names of students in a secured Teacher roster. The first and last names are entered into separate fields, and unique screen names are then generated for each student, based on the entry in the first name field.
  * It is the Teacher's responsibility to ensure that only the first names are added in the first name field. Artsonia is not responsible if a Teacher types last names or any other personally identifiable information about a child into the first name field.
  * The information typed into the last name field is not posted publicly on the Website. It is used as a means to organize the roster for the Teacher's benefit only, and can only be accessed within the secure Teacher section.

**3\. Information Provided By Parents**

Parents who are interested in displaying their child's artwork on Artsonia are required to register as members. The information provided during the registration process is used to communicate with the Parent as well as to create an Artist gallery on Artsonia. Parents should be aware that, because the information the Parent types in the first name field textbox when registering is posted on the Website and is publicly accessible to all users of the Website, that information could be collected, used, and disclosed by others. Artsonia is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of such information. Artsonia does not publicly post Parent last names or email addresses on the Website, and does not sell that information to or share that information with third parties except where Parents have explicitly authorized Artsonia to share such information with our marketing partners. 

  * To create an Artist gallery, Parents type the first and last name of their child into the appropriate textboxes. The first and last names are entered into separate fields, and a unique screen name is then generated for the child Artist, based on the text typed into the first name field.
  * It is the Parent's responsibility to ensure that only the first name is typed into the first name field. Artsonia is not responsible if a Parent types a last name or any other personally identifiable information about their child into the first name field.
  * The information in the last name field is not posted publicly on the Website.
  * In addition, as part of the Parent account creation process, Artsonia records the IP address used to register and agree to Artsonia Terms & Conditions of Use.
  * Parents may enter the names, email addresses and relationships to Artist of additional Fan Club Members. The Fan Club Members first names and relationships will be included alongside the Artist's gallery.

**4\. Information Provided by Kids (Children Under 13)**

Artsonia is committed to complying with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 )COPPA). Our information collection practices are described below. Artsonia urges kids to check with their Parents before entering any information on any Website, and we urge Parents to discuss with their kids the potential danger of revealing personal information to anyone they don't know. 

Artsonia's policy is not to collect any more information from kids than is necessary to enable the chosen services, features and functionalities. 

  * We DO NOT allow children under 13 to join a Fan Club.
  * We DO NOT allow children under 13 to leave a Comment on the Website.
  * We DO NOT allow children under 13 to leave a Teacher Compliment on the Website.
  * We DO NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information from kids.
  * We DO NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information collected from kids.

**Artwork Submission:** Kids under 13 years of age are allowed to submit artwork for publication via the Teacher Classroom Mode feature. Therefore, it is the Teacher's responsibility to review and approve all artwork submissions entered via the Classroom Mode feature, and to abide by the provisions set forth in the Terms and Conditions with respect to such submissions. 

**Artwork Titles and Statements:** Kids under 13 years of age are allowed to leave an artwork title about their artwork. However, they can only do so via the Teacher Classroom Mode feature (as defined in the Terms and Conditions). Therefore, it is the Teacher's responsibility to review and approve all artwork title submissions entered via the Classroom Mode feature, and to abide by the provisions set forth in the Terms and Conditions with respect to such submissions. 

**5\. Personally Identifiable Information About Artists**

It is Artsonia's policy to protect the identity of the Artists showcasing their artwork on Artsonia. Artists will be identified only by their screen name (which often but not necessarily consists of the Artist's first name and a numerical suffix). Artsonia does not knowingly post the full name, mailing address or email address of Artists on its Website. 

As noted above and further specified in the Terms and Conditions, we require that Teachers and Parents only type the first name of the Artist into the first name field when submitting artwork. We also recommend that Teachers and Parents remove, erase or cover any appearance of the Artist's last name on the artwork and/or digital images of artwork itself before submitting it to the Website. Artsonia is not responsible for any damages resulting directly or indirectly from the negligence of the submitter of the artwork, including if the submitter erroneously type the last name of the Artist into the first name textbox, or if the Artist has listed his or her full name as part of the artwork image and that artwork is submitted to Artsonia. 

**6\. Information Collected for Purposes of Online Orders**

Online shoppers on the Website must be over age 18 and must use a valid credit card or other valid payment method accepted by us to purchase products online. When an online order is placed, we collect information associated with the requested transaction, such as the customer's name, mailing address, products ordered, shipping addresses, email address, and credit card information. We ask for this information so that we may fulfill the order. We will send a confirmation email to the address provided after the order is successfully placed. 

**7\. Contracted Companies that Facilitate Communications and Transactions With You.**

Artsonia may hire companies to help deliver products or services, provide support for the internal operations, or help fulfillment for online product orders. In those instances, there is a need to share your information with these contracted companies, but they in turn do not disclose or use that information for any other purpose. Your opt-out choices below will not apply to sharing of your information by us with any of these companies. **Note: our contracted companies are contractually bound to maintain the confidentiality and security of all customer information.**

**8\. Information Posted Publicly on Artsonia**

Users should be aware that any personal information (including the names of persons or schools) that is posted on Artsonia by Users is accessible to other Users of the Website and could be collected, used, and disclosed by others. For example, if a User includes his or her full name or the name of a school in a Comment for an Artist, then once that Comment is approved, that information would be accessible to all Users of the Website. Artsonia is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of information provided in Comments approved for posting. We recommend that all personally identifiable information be removed from all content submitted or approved for submission by Parents or Teachers for posting to the Website. We also recommend that Parents and Teachers not submit or approve for submission any artwork or other material that contains photographs or images (especially the faces) of children under 18 years old, including the Artist themselves. 

**9\. Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that Artsonia writes to a User's computer to make it easier for the User to navigate within the Website. Artsonia cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information such as passwords. Visitors to the Website have the option of disabling cookies via browser preferences. However, if cookies are disabled, some features of the Website may not function properly. 

**10\. Aggregate Statistics**

Artsonia may report aggregate statistics about visitors, traffic patterns, electronic postcard usage and related site information to partners, sponsors, advertisers, subsidiaries, affiliates and other third parties, but these statistics do not include any personally identifiable information. 

**11\. Choice/Opt-Out**

Artsonia provides Users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving any future communications from Artsonia and its partners at any time. If a User wants to remove their information from Artsonia's database and not receive future communications, please contact Artsonia at [info@artsonia.com](mailto:info@artsonia.com). 

**12\. How Artsonia Protects Your Privacy Internally**

Artsonia wants your information to remain as secure as reasonably possible. We combine industry-standard technical safeguards with a code of conduct for those employees that are permitted to access our customers' business information. 

Artsonia's Website is hosted on servers that are co-located at a third party facility, with whom we have a contract providing for enhanced security measures. For example, your student information is stored on a server equipped with industry standard firewalls. In addition, the hosting facility provides a 24 X 7 security system, camera surveillance, and locked cage areas. 

On the employee side, every Artsonia employee with access to data is trained on our privacy and security procedures. Only authorized Artsonia employees, agents or independent contractors are permitted to access your account information or student data, and all such employees, agents or independent contractors must agree in writing to abide by our Privacy Policy. Those employees that violate our Privacy Policy are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. 

**13\. Additional Information**

For more information about Artsonia's privacy policy or questions and comments, please contact [info@artsonia.com](mailto:info@artsonia.com) or write Artsonia at: 

> Artsonia LLC  
>  Attn: Member Services  
>  1350 Tri-State Parkway, Ste 106  
>  Gurnee, IL 60031
